[
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Who wrote the title page of The Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Mormon",
    "options": ["Joseph Smith", "Mormon", "Moroni"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The abridgment of the record is written to the Jew and Gentile.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The record is written by way of commandment, and also by the spirit of ____ and of revelation.",
    "answer": "prophecy"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The record was written and sealed up, and hid up unto the Lord, that they may not be destroyed",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Where in the Book of Mormon is the word Lamanites first mentioned?",
    "answer": "Title Page"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The word “Jaredites” first appears to in the Title page of the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "An abridgment is taken from the Book of ____, which is a record of the people of Jared.",
    "answer": "ether"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The people of Jared were scattered at the time the Lord confounded their language.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "At time the Lord confounded the language of the Jaredites, they were trying to build a ____ to get to heaven.",
    "answer": "tower"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The Lord has done many great things unto the remnant of the House of ____.",
    "answer": "Israel"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The Lord wants to show the remnant House of Israel the many great things that he has done for their fathers.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The Lord wants the House of Israel to know the ____ he has made with them and not be cast-off forever.",
    "answer": "Covenants",
    "options": ["Bible", "Articles of Faith", "Covenants"]
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The Lord wants to convince Jews and Gentiles that Jesus is the ____.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Jesus is the Christ, the Eternal God, manifesting himself unto all nations.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Mormon states that if there are faults in the record, they are the ____ of Men.",
    "answer": "Mistakes"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Mormon writes, condemn not the things of God?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Mormon wants us to be found spotless at the _____ seat of Christ",
    "answer": "Judgment"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Who translated the title page of the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Joseph Smith",
    "options": ["Moroni", "Mormon", "Joseph Smith"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Brief Analysis",
    "question": "In the brief analysis of the Book of Mormon we are told that there are namely three classes of record plates.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Brief Analysis",
    "question": "The Brass Plates of Laban are mentioned frequently in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Brief Analysis",
    "question": "The body of the Book of Mormon, from Mosiah to Mormon, chapter #7, inclusive, is the translation of whose ____ abridgment of the Plates of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Mormon"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Brief Analysis",
    "question": "The period covered in the Book of Mormon extends from B.C. 600 to A.D. 421.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Brief Analysis",
    "question": "Who was the last of the Nephite historians?",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Brief Analysis",
    "question": "Moroni was the last of the Nephite historians that sealed the sacred record, and hid up unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Brief Analysis",
    "question": "In the Brief Analysis of the Book of Mormon, Joseph Smith mentions the hill Cumorah by name.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Ether 15:11",
    "question": "The hill Cumorah was referred as the hill Ramah by the Jaredites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mor 1:3, 4:23",
    "question": "The hill Cumorah was referred as the hill Shim by the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Look! @ BOM",
    "question": "In what beautiful state, is the hill Cumorah located.",
    "answer": "New York"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "On the night of September 21, 1823, who appeared to Joseph Smith Junior ____?",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "When Moroni first appeared to Joseph Smith he referred to him as a personage.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "When Joseph sought the Lord in fervent prayer, he discovered a_____ appearing in his room.",
    "answer": "light"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The light that appeared to Joseph, was lighter than noon-day.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The personage that appeared to Joseph Smith was ____, and he was standing in the air.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "When Moroni appeared to Joseph Smith, he was standing in the air.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni’s robe was of the most exquisite ____.",
    "answer": "whiteness",
    "options": ["Color", "Whiteness", "Design"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith writes: That he believed that anything earthly could be made to appear so exceedingly white or brilliant.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith said that he could see Moroni’s hands were naked and his arms also, a little above the wrists.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni’s ____ and neck were also bare, when he appeared to Joseph Smith.",
    "answer": "Head"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith could see that Moroni was wearing clothing that is worn by worthy temple workers.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Because Moroni’s head and neck were bare, Joseph Smith could see into Moroni’s ____.",
    "answer": "bosom"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Not only was Moroni’s robe exceedingly white, his whole person was glorious beyond description.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith states that ____ countenance was truly like lightning.",
    "answer": "moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni’s countenance was truly like lightning, when he appeared to Joseph Smith.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The light that surrounded ____ was brighter than the light of the room.",
    "answer": "moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "When Joseph Smith first saw Moroni, he was afraid.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Who was afraid of Moroni, when he first appeared in his room?",
    "answer": "Joseph Smith"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "It took a very long time for Joseph Smith to get over of being afraid of Moroni.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "At first, Joseph Smith was afraid of Moroni, but soon the ____ left him.",
    "answer": "Fear",
    "options": ["Fear", "Sadness", "Glory"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The messenger called Joseph Smith by name.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The messenger told Joseph Smith, that his name would be had for good and ____.",
    "answer": "evil"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The messenger to Joseph that all nation’s, kindreds, and ____, would speak evil of his name.",
    "answer": "tongues"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The messenger to Joseph that all nation’s, kindreds, and tongues would speak evil of his name.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni said that there was a_____ deposited in the ground, written upon gold plates.",
    "answer": "Book",
    "options": ["Manuscript", "Book", "Tablet"]
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The book that was deposited in the ground was written on what type of metal?",
    "answer": "Gold",
    "options": ["Silver", "Brass", "Gold"]
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The book gave an account of the former ____ of the continent.",
    "answer": "Inhabitants",
    "options": ["Inhabitants", "Dinosaurs", "Birds"]
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Ask someone that knows",
    "question": "What is the name of continent in which the book was deposited and in which we in the united states live?",
    "answer": "North America"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The book gives an account of the former inhabitants of this continent, and the source from whence they sprang.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The ____ of the everlasting Gospel was contained in the book; that was deposited in the earth.",
    "answer": "fulness"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The fulness of the everlasting Gospel is contained in the Book.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The fulness of the everlasting Gospel was delivered by the ____, to the former ancient inhabitants.",
    "answer": ["savior", "lord"]
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "What shade of color were the two stones in the bow?",
    "answer": "Silver",
    "options": ["Metallic", "Gold", "Silver"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The two stones in silver bows were fastened to a breastplate.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Another name that is given to the two stones and breastplate is the ____.",
    "answer": "Urim and Thummim"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The Urim and Thummim is what constitutes the two stones and the breastplate.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "No ref because they are not.",
    "question": "The Urim and Thummim are mentioned by name in the text of Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The possession and the use of these stones were what constituted what word?",
    "answer": "Seers"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The Seers were not used in ancientformer times.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The Seers were madeprepared by whom?",
    "answer": ["god", "lord"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The Seers were prepared by God; for the purpose of translating the book, of which is now known as the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "With the possession and use of the Seers, people cancould translate ancient writings.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Angel Moroni told Joseph Smith to show the plates to anyone that he pleased.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph was told not to show the plates to anyone, unless he was ____ to do so.",
    "answer": "Commanded"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph was commanded by Moroni, to show only the breastplate and not the Urim and Thummim.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Unless Joseph was commanded; Moroni said that he must not show the plates and Urim and Thummin to anyonehe would be destroyed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "While Joseph was conversing with Moroni about the plates, he had a ____.",
    "answer": "Vision",
    "options": ["Vision", "Seizure", "Migraine Headache"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "In his vision, Joseph Smith could see the place where the plates were deposited.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The vision was so clear and distinct, that Joseph knew where the place was when he visited it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "After the communication, Joseph saw the light in the room begin to gather around this person.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Except around Moroni, the room began to get dark again.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "A conduit opened right up into ____, and Moroni ascended until he entirely disappeared.",
    "answer": "heaven"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph states and refers to the light in his room as being heavenly.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "After the messenger and the light left, Joseph fell asleep.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph lay in bed and was overwhelmed with astonishment at what he had both ____, and heard.",
    "answer": "seen"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The second time the messenger appeared to Joseph, he repeated the same words as the first time, without variation.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni told Joseph ____ would try to tempt him.",
    "answer": "satan"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni informed Joseph of great judgments which were coming upon the ____.",
    "answer": "Earth",
    "options": ["People", "Heavens", "Earth"]
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni said that great judgments were coming upon the earth such as; desolations by famine, sword, and ____.",
    "answer": "Pestilence"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "At what time did Moroni say that the judgements were coming to the earth?",
    "answer": "This generation",
    "options": ["Noah's time", "This generation", "The generation to come"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph writes that he and his father’s family were indigent.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni told Joseph that he must have no other object in view in getting the plates but glorify ____.",
    "answer": "god"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni told Joseph Smith that he must not be influenced by any other motive than that of building the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "How many times did the angel Moroni visit Joseph Smith in one single night?",
    "answer": "Three",
    "options": ["One", "Two", "Three"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Angel Moroni visited Joseph Smith three times in September of 1823.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "After Moroni’s third visit, as he ascended into heaven; What kind of fowl did Joseph hear crowed.",
    "answer": "Rooster",
    "options": ["Swan", "Rooster", "Turkey"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni left, and Joseph realized that their interviews must of have taken all night because the day had approach.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph attempted to work as other times, but found that his strength was ____.",
    "answer": "Exhausted",
    "options": ["Exhausted", "Gone", "Stronger"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Because of his exhausted strength, Joseph’s father told him to go home.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "While attempting to cross the _____ out of the field, Joseph's strength left him and he fell to the ground.",
    "answer": "Fence",
    "options": ["River", "Highway", "Fence"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph fell to the ground and was unconscious for three days.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "In the Origin of the Book of Mormon: It does not sayhow long Joseph exactly lay unconscious.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Who appeared to Joseph Smith when he arose from his unconsciousness?",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph was ____ by Moroni to tell his father, of the vision and commandments he had received.",
    "answer": "Commanded",
    "options": ["Told", "Exhorted", "Commanded"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph obeyed Moroni, and returned to his father in the field, and rehearsed the whole matter to him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph left out some important details, when he rehearsed the story to his father.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph’s father told him to go to the place where the Messenger had told him to go.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph new the place where the plates were deposited because of the dream that he had.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Because of his_____, Joseph knew the place where the plates were buried.",
    "answer": "Vision",
    "options": ["Hindsight", "Vision", "Foresight"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The hill where the plates were deposited was more elevated than the other surrounding hills.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Convenient to what village is the Hill Cumorah located?",
    "answer": "Manchester"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "What person is represented by statue, atop the Hill Cumorah?",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith tells us the plates were hidden under a considerable size stone and facing what direction?",
    "answer": "West",
    "options": ["North", "South", "West"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "When Joseph Smith removed the earth that was fixed under the stone, he had a difficult time.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "When Joseph Smith looked into the stone box; it contained the plates, the ____, and the breastplate.",
    "answer": "Urim and Thummim"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith made an attempt to get the things out of the box, but was forbidden by whom?",
    "answer": ["messanger", "moroni"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The messenger told Joseph Smith that the time had not come yet to get the things out of the box.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "How many years would pass before Joseph Smith could get the things out of the box?",
    "answer": "Four",
    "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni told Joseph Smith to come precisely one year from the time that he first saw him and that he would meet with him again.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith did as he was ____, and he went at the end of each year and at each time, he found the same messenger there waiting for him.",
    "answer": "Commanded",
    "options": ["Forbidden", "Commanded", "Instructed"]
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith received instructions and ____, from the messenger, at each of their interviews.",
    "answer": "Intelligence",
    "options": ["Gold", "Money", "Intelligence"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The messenger told Joseph what the Lord was going to do, and how and what manner His kingdom was to be conducted in the last days.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The messenger delivered the plates to Joseph and told him that he was to be responsible for them and if he would let them go carelessly, he would not be cut off.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The messenger told Joseph that he should use all of his endeavors to preserve the ____.",
    "answer": "Plates",
    "options": ["Hill Cumorah", "Plates", "House of his Father"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith was told by the messenger what would be required of him to do by his hand.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph was told by the messenger: That the ____ would be protected until he should call for them again.",
    "answer": "Plates"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "As soon as it was found out that he had the plates, multitudes of people were out to get them away from them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Who do you think told people that Joseph Smith had a book written upon gold plates?",
    "answer": ["adversary", "satan"]
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith said that every_____ that could be invented was resorted to take away the plates from him.",
    "answer": "Stratagem",
    "options": ["Stratagem", "Device", "Intelligence"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "When the messenger called for the plates, Joseph Smith did not deliver them unto him until he was commanded.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "According to Joseph Smith, Who has the platesis in charge of them to this day?",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The Book of Mormon was translated into modern speech by the gift and power of_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "As attested by Divine affirmation, the ancient record has been brought forth from the earth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The Book of Mormon was first published to the world in what year of our Lord?",
    "answer": "1830",
    "options": ["1821", "1823", "1830"]
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Look! @ BOM",
    "question": "What is the name of the artist who painted most of the Book of Mormon paintings?",
    "answer": ["Arnold", "Friberg"]
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Testimony of Three Witnesses in the BOM",
    "question": "Who were the Three Witnesses of the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "Oliver Cowdery, David Whitmer and Martin Harris",
    "options": [
      "Oliver Cowdery, David Whitmer and Lorenzo Snow",
      "Joseph Smith Sr, Brigham Young and Nephi",
      "Oliver Cowdery, David Whitmer and Martin Harris"
    ]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Testimony of the Eight Witnesses in the BOM",
    "question": "In the testimony of the Eight Witnesses, they describe the plates of having the appearance of ancient work, and of curious workmanship.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Testimony of the Eight Witnesses in the BOM",
    "question": "In the testimony of the Eight Witnesses, they state that they gave their names to the world, to witness unto the world that, that they handled the plates with their hands and saw the engraving thereon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Testimony of the Eight Witnesses in the BOM",
    "question": "The Eight Witnesses state that they “lie not” and bear witness unto whom?",
    "answer": "god"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon",
    "question": "What is the title of the first book in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon",
    "question": "What is the title of the last book in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The longest book in the Book of Mormon is the Book of Mosiah?",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "What is the longest book in the Book of Mormon",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "What Book of Mormon book has the least verses",
    "answer": "Jarom",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "What is the name of the book that has the second least amount of verses",
    "answer": "The Words Of Mormon",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The words: “was the son of “are used how many times in the Book of Ether.",
    "options": [15, 20, 21],
    "answer": "21",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Omni",
    "question": "What Book of Mormon author wrote the least amount of words in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Chemish"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Omni",
    "question": "This Book of Mormon author only wrote one verse.",
    "answer": "Chemish"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:4",
    "question": "A prophet would the Lord God raise up among the Jews-even a _____, or, in other words, a Savior of the world.",
    "answer": "Messiah"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "There are only three women mentioned by name in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "Abish-Alma19:16, Eve-1Nep5:11, Isabel-Alma39:3, Mary-Mos3:8, Sariah-1Nep2:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi was born of _____ parents.",
    "options": [" Bad", "Naughty", "Goodly"],
    "answer": "Goodly",
    "ref": "1Nep:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi was taught somewhat in all the learning of his father.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi saw many_____ in the course of his days.",
    "options": ["bad things", "afflictions", "parties"],
    "answer": "afflictions",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13, Alma 12:221, 42:2-3",
    "question": "What modern day weapon has been around since the beginning of man?",
    "answer": "Sword"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi was highly favored of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1",
    "question": "What Book of Mormon historian was highly favored of the Lord?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "How many days was, Nephi highly favored of the Lord?  c-(B)",
    "options": ["half", "all", "neither half nor all"],
    "answer": "all",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1",
    "question": "Nephi had_____ knowledge of the goodness and the mysteries of God.",
    "answer": "Great"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi was not a very smart prophet.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said: “I make a record of my proceedings in my days”.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The record that Nephi made about his reign and ministry is known to us as the: “First Book Of _____”.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:2",
    "question": "Nephi made a record in the _____ of his father.",
    "answer": "Language"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi’s writing’s consists of the learning of what tribe of people?",
    "options": ["Jews", "Egyptians", "Mongols"],
    "answer": "Jews",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi was taught by his father in the language of the _____",
    "options": ["Israelites", "Egyptians", "Mongols"],
    "answer": "Egyptians",
    "ref": "1Nep1:2 & Mosiah1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi taught Lehi the language of the Egyptians.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:2"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said that his record is somewhat true as far as he can remember.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:3"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that: The record which I make is true; and I make it with mine own hand”.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:3"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi made the record according to his_____.  (a) -(C)",
    "options": ["memory", "will", "knowledge"],
    "answer": "knowledge",
    "ref": "1Nep1:3"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "It came to pass in the commencement of the_____ year of the reign Zedekiah. ",
    "options": ["1st", "2nd", "3rd"],
    "answer": "1st",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4",
    "question": "Who was the king of Judah at the time that Nephi wrote the book of Nephi?",
    "answer": "Zedekiah"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What body of land did king Zedekiah reign over.",
    "options": ["Egypt", "Israel", "Judah"],
    "answer": "Judah",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4",
    "question": "What important city was located in the land of Judah?",
    "answer": "Jerusalem"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "In the beginning of the Book of Nephi: He writes that Lehi lived in Jerusalem all his days.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi was Nephi's uncle.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi was the father of Nephi.",
    "answert": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What kind of people came to Jerusalem at the same year of the commencement of the reign of King Zedekiah?",
    "options": ["Jews", "Prophets", "Hebrews"],
    "answer": "Prophets",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Many prophets came to the city of Jerusalem and prophesied that if the people did not repent, the city would be destroyed.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4",
    "question": "What city in the land of Judah would be destroyed if the people did not repent?",
    "answer": "Jerusalem"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The city of Jerusalem; was a great city according to Nephi.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Lehi prayed on behalf of his_____.",
    "options": ["Wives", "Pets", "People"],
    "answer": "People",
    "ref": "1Nep1:5",
    "id": 178
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:5",
    "question": "Who did Lehi pray to and asked that the city would not be destroyed?",
    "answer": ["god", "lord"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi prayed to the Lord with all his heart.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:6",
    "question": "As Lehi prayed unto the Lord, there came a pillar of_____.",
    "answer": "Fire"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "When Lehi was praying unto the Lord, a pillar of fire appeared.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:6"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The pillar of fire did not dwell upon a rock; instead it flew over Lehi’s head.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:6"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of the pillar of fire, Lehi saw and heard much.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:6"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Because of the things Lehi saw and heard he did quake and_____ exceedingly.",
    "options": ["Danced The Macarena", "Did The Twist", "Tremble"],
    "answer": "Tremble",
    "ref": "1Nep1:6",
    "id": 185
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Lehi cast himself upon his bed, being overcome by the_____.",
    "options": ["Heat", "Spirit", "Devil"],
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "ref": "1Nep1:7",
    "id": 186
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi cast himself to bed because he was overcome by the Spirit.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:7"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "And being thus overcome with the Spirit, Lehi was carried away in a_____.",
    "answer": "Vision"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Lehi saw in his vision the_____ opened.",
    "options": ["Earth", "Heavens", "Neither A Nor B"],
    "answer": "Heavens",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "id": 189
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "In his vision, who did Lehi see sitting upon his throne?",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "Lehi saw God sitting upon his_____.",
    "answer": "Throne"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "In his vision Lehi saw the Devil being cast out of heaven.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "_____was sitting upon his throne, surrounded with numberless concourses of angels.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "God sat on his throne, and was surrounded by one million angels.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "As God sat on his throne, angels were singing and praising their God.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "In his vision, Lehi saw____ singing and praising their God.",
    "answer": "Angels"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:9",
    "question": "Lehi saw one/person descending out of the midst of_____.",
    "answer": "Heaven"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The person’s luster that Lehi saw descending out of heaven was above that of the sun at noon-day.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:9"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The word “noon-day” only appears once in the text of the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:9"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "How many times does the word “noon-day” appear in the text of the Book of Mormon?",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"],
    "answer": "1",
    "ref": "1Nep1:9",
    "id": 200
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "How many persons followed the first person that Lehi saw in his vision?",
    "options": ["3", "Six", "12"],
    "answer": "12",
    "ref": "1Nep1:10",
    "id": 201
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Twelve others followed the first person that Lehi saw in his vision.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:10"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The brightness of the twelve people that Lehi saw in his vision exceeded that of the stars in the firmament.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:10"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Whose brightness exceeded that of the stars in the firmament?",
    "options": ["The Devil", "The Twelve", "Laman’s"],
    "answer": "The Twelve",
    "ref": "1Nep1:10",
    "id": 204
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The first person that Lehi saw descending out of heaven and the twelve others that followed him; came down and went forth upon the face of the earth.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:11",
    "question": "All the people that Lehi saw descending out of heaven came down and went forth upon the face of the_____.",
    "answer": "Earth"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What person stood before Lehi and gave him a book and bade him to read it.",
    "options": ["1st Person", "2nd Person", "The 3rd"],
    "answer": "1st Person",
    "ref": "1Nep1:11",
    "id": 207
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi choose not to read the book that the first person gave him to read.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:12",
    "question": "When Lehi read the book that he was given; he was filled with the____ of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi did not pray before he read the book that he was given and consequently, did not feel the Spirit of the Lord.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:12"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13",
    "question": "In the book that he was given Lehi saw the abominations of what city in the land of Judah?",
    "answer": "Jerusalem"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13",
    "question": "Lehi said: “Woe, woe, unto_____, for I have seen thine abominations!”",
    "answer": "Jereusalem"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi saw and read many things concerning the city of Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi saw and read that the city of Jerusalem would be destroyed and also it's inhabitants.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Many of the people of Jerusalem would perish by the_____ and be carried away captive.",
    "options": ["Knife", "Sword", "Famine"],
    "answer": "Sword",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13",
    "id": 215
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Only those that were unrighteous would perish by the sword and be carried into captivity.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13",
    "question": "Lehi saw the people of Jerusalem perish and be carried away captive to_____.",
    "answer": "Babylon"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Lehi read and saw many_____ and marvelous things and exclaimed many things unto the Lord.",
    "options": ["Bad", "Good", "Great"],
    "answer": "Great",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14",
    "id": 218
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Lehi said “great and marvelous are thy works, O Lord God_____",
    "options": ["Almighty", "Gosh Darn It", "Its All Good"],
    "answer": "Almighty",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14",
    "id": 219
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "According to Lehi, where is the throne of God located?",
    "options": ["Close To The Moon", "The Heavens", "Underneath The Stars"],
    "answer": "The Heavens",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14",
    "id": 220
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi said the throne of God is located in the heavens.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Lehi said that God’s power, goodness, and mercy are over all the_____ of the earth.",
    "options": ["People", "Inhabitants", "Unrighteous"],
    "answer": "Inhabitants",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14",
    "id": 222
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi said that God is merciful.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi saw and read that God was not very merciful to the inhabitants of Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14",
    "question": "Because God is _____, he will not suffer those that come unto him to perish.",
    "answer": "Merciful"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi did not praise God because of the things he had seen.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:15"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of the things Lehi saw his soul did rejoice.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:15"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:15",
    "question": "Lehi’s soul did rejoice, and his_____ was filled because of the things he saw.",
    "answer": "Heart"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi made a full account of the thing which his father wrote.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:16"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:16",
    "question": "Lehi wrote many things which he saw in visions and in_____.",
    "answer": "Dreams"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi said that Lehi had written many things which he prophesied and spoke unto his_____.",
    "options": ["Daughters", "Uncles", "Children"],
    "answer": "Children",
    "ref": "1Nep1:16",
    "id": 231
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi made an account of his proceedings.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:17"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:17",
    "question": "Who made an abridgement of the record of his father?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:17",
    "question": "The plates that Nephi made for the record, were made by his_____.",
    "answer": "Hand"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi first made an abridgment of the record of Lehi then he made an account of his life.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:17"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi prophesied and declared to the people of Jerusalem the marvelous things which he had seen and heard.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:18"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:19",
    "question": "The Jews did_____, Lehi because of the things he testified of them.",
    "answer": "Mock"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi testified to the Jews of things which he saw and heard, and also of the things which he read in a book.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:19"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:19",
    "question": "The book which Lehi read; manifested plainly of the coming of the_____.",
    "answer": "Messiah"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Jews were angry with Lehi even as with the prophets of old.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:20"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:20",
    "question": "Because of the things that he had said, the Jews sought to kill_____.",
    "answer": "Lehi"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:20",
    "question": "The Jews: _____out, and stoned, and slain, the prophets of old in the city of Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "Cast"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that he would show unto us that the tender mercies of the Lord are over all those whom he hath chosen.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:20"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Because of their_____, the Lord will make those that he has chosen mighty even unto the power of deliverance.",
    "options": ["Riches", "Pride", "Faith"],
    "answer": "Faith",
    "ref": "1Nep1:20",
    "id": 244
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Jews were angry with Lehi because he testified of their wickedness and abominations.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:19-20"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord spoke to Lehi in a dream and told him he was blessed for things that he had done.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:1",
    "question": "Lehi was faithful and declared unto the people the things which the_____ had commanded him to say.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The people in Jerusalem sough to take away Lehi’s life.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:2",
    "question": "The ____ came to Lehi in a dream and commanded him to depart into the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi did not obey the word of the Lord, and did not depart until he was ready.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep2:3"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:5",
    "question": "By what borders and shore of a sea did Lehi and his family travel to?",
    "answer": "Red Sea"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:5",
    "question": "What was Nephi’s mother’s name?",
    "answer": "Sariah"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "How many days did Lehi and his family travel before pitching their tents for the first time?",
    "options": ["2", "3", "4"],
    "answer": "3",
    "ref": "1Nep2:6",
    "id": 253
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Lehi built an altar of_____.",
    "options": ["Rocks", "Clay", "Stones"],
    "answer": "Stones",
    "ref": "1Nep2:7",
    "id": 254
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi made an offering unto the Lord and gave thanks unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep2:7"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Which son die Lehi name a river after; that emptied into the Red Sea?",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Sam,", "Laman"],
    "answer": "Laman",
    "ref": "1Nep2:8",
    "id": 256
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The name of the river that emptied into the Red Sea was called_____.",
    "options": ["The Snake,", "The Mississippi,", "Laman"],
    "answer": "Laman",
    "ref": "1Nep2:8",
    "id": 257
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:8",
    "question": "Lehi named a river after one of his sons",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:9",
    "question": "Which one of his son’s was Lehi speaking to when he said” O that thou mightest be like unto this river, continually running into the fountain of all righteousness!",
    "answer": "Laman"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:10",
    "question": "Lehi was referring to Lemuel when he said “O that thou might be like unto this valley, firm and stead-fest, and immovable in keeping the commandments of the Lord!”",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Lehi spoke encouraging words to Laman and Lemuel because of their_____.",
    "options": ["Looks", "Stiffneckedness", "Clothes"],
    "answer": "Stiffneckedness",
    "ref": "1Nep2:11",
    "id": 261
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "For behold Laman and Lemuel did murmur in many things against Lehi.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:11",
    "question": "Lehi was a visionary man.",
    "answer": "t"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:11",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers murmured because Lehi had led them out of Jerusalem, to leave the land of their inheritance, and their gold and_____.",
    "answer": "Silver"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel left behind their precious things and thought they were going to perish in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers said that Lehi had led them into the wilderness because of the foolish imaginations of his_____.",
    "options": ["Heart", "Head", "Mind"],
    "answer": "Heart",
    "ref": "1Nep2:11",
    "id": 266
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:12",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel murmured because they did not know the dealings of that_____, who had created them.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel did not believe that what great city could be destroyed.",
    "options": ["Salt Lake City,", "Sugar City,", "Jerusalem"],
    "answer": "Jerusalem",
    "ref": "1Nep2:13",
    "id": 268
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi’s two older brothers did not believe that Jerusalem could be destroyed according to the words of the_____.",
    "options": ["3 Wise Men", "Prophets", "Holy Men"],
    "answer": "Prophets",
    "ref": "1Nep2:13",
    "id": 269
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi writes that his older brothers were like the Jews who sought to take away the life of his father.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:13"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:14",
    "question": "Lehi spoke to Laman and Lemuel in the valley of_____, with great power.",
    "answer": "Lemuel"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:14",
    "question": "Lehi spoke to his eldest sons with great power because he was filled with the____ of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel’s frame_____ because of the spirit of the Lord in Lehi.",
    "options": ["Rocked", "Rolled", "Shook"],
    "answer": "Shook",
    "ref": "1Nep2:14",
    "id": 273
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The words that Lehi spoke confounded Laman and Lemuel.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi writes that Lehi lived in a pretty nice house.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep2:15"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of the words Lehi spoke to Laman and Lemuel they did not utter a word against him.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:16",
    "question": "Who was exceedingly young and large in stature?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi did not have a great desire to know of the mysteries of God.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep2:16"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:16",
    "question": "Nephi cried unto God so that he could know of his_____.",
    "answer": "Mysteries"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi’s heart was softened when he cried unto the Lord. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:16"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who did the Lord visit when he cried unto him?",
    "options": ["Laman", "Lamuel", "Nephi"],
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:16",
    "id": 281
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:16",
    "question": "Because his heart was softened: Nephi, believed all the_____ which had been spoken by his father.",
    "answer": "Words"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sam the brother of Nephi; did not believe in the words that Nephi had spoken to him. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep2:17"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What brother believed Nephi’s words when he spoke to them concerning the things which the Lord had manifested unto him?",
    "options": ["Laman,", "Lemuel", "Sam"],
    "answer": "Sam",
    "ref": "1Nep2:17",
    "id": 284
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:18",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel would not _____ unto the words that Nephi said to them.",
    "answer": "Hearken"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi cried unto the Lord because of the _____ of the hearts of his two older brothers.",
    "options": ["Heads", "Hardness", "Softness"],
    "answer": "Hardness",
    "ref": "1Nep2:18",
    "id": 286
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi was grieved because of the hardness of the hearts of his two older brothers. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:18"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:19",
    "question": "Who did the Lord visit because of his faith and his lowliness of heart?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of his faith, Nephi diligently sought the Lord. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:19"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who did the Lord say that he would lead to a promise land?",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Lehi", "Laman"],
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:20 & 1Nep18:22-23",
    "id": 290
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:19-20",
    "question": "Who is the first person the Lord said these words to “in as-much as ye shall keep my commandments, ye shall prosper”.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord did not prepare a choice land that was above all other lands for Nephi. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep2:20"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "In as much as Laman and Lemuel rebel against_____; they shall be cut off from the presence of the Lord.",
    "options": ["Lehi", "Neph"],
    "answer": "Lehi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:20",
    "id": 293
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "Who did the Lord say needed to keep his commandments and he would be made a teacher and ruler over his older brothers? ",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:22"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "Who was chosen to be a ruler and a teacher over his brothers?_____",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:22"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "In the day that Laman and Lemuel rebel against the Lord, he would curse them with a sore curse.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:23"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel’s seed shall have no power over the seed of Nephi unless they_____ against the Lord also. ",
    "answer": "Rebel",
    "ref": "1Nep2:23"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi returned to his____ after he had spoken to the Lord.",
    "options": ["House", "Tent", "Sanctuary"],
    "answer": "Tent",
    "ref": "1Nep3:1",
    "id": 298
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "In a dream, Lehi was_____ by the Lord to send Nephi and his older brothers back to Jerusalem.",
    "options": ["Told", "Commanded", "Asked"],
    "answer": "Commanded",
    "ref": "1Nep3:2",
    "id": 299
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "Who had a record of the Jews and also a genealogy of Lehi’s forefathers?",
    "answer": "Laban",
    "ref": "1Nep3:3"
  }
]
